[Music]
ah
he
[Music]
welcome good day good evening to
everybody Welcome to the latest episode
of asab abijit I hope you're all doing
well I'm starting this live stream at a
very unusual time never started at 6:00
p.m. India time before but today is a
special occasion it's not every day that
India is playing the World Cup final
which have which starts in two hours
time so I thought let me not have this
live stream coincide with that so that
those who want to watch this can also
watch this and also watch the World Cup
so let's see who all is there on the
live stream I can see sajal utkarsh
Patel abhinav threeways two this is AJ
ronit sahu sarak Gupta Jo Singh s boria
hello prna tanay Desh Pand forum kacha
abishek gapur aush Kumar Sharma Akshay
Sharma Karan nwat hello curiosity kicha
om biker hi Vishnu moan asor hello vaj
deshmuk bat first pray Paul Terminator
geopolitical Dubai namaskar Sujin B
Vladimir chavda karat
hello KL
Chi tanai Chad Jin Terminator let's see
who all is there who else saw me join
aluminati Creek hello ragavendra a
sporty Club India Atul
chasti nihal
valti Akash chasia
258 sumitra Munda Chan Desh pande force
field squid games Alo b s
sarasan sardai online yo
bro and everybody else okay okay lots of
people so let's go get started I can see
Guru Prasad mavin abav dude Maxa Kushi
yav and lots of other people Malik Sayad
debaker debaker world and everybody else
okay so let's get going with the
questions today I'm going to take
questions only from the live chat so get
get going ask your best questions and I
will take as many as possible we're
going to cap this live stream to at 90
minutes we're going to end in 90 minutes
from now so let's take as many questions
as possible let us see um okay we have a
question about MMA villain says Alex
Perera versus ji prashka who do you
think wins tomorrow I think Alex Pereira
could win uh even ji is great but I
think Alex will
win
okay
um rishab goena says I recently
explained geopolitics between China
India and Russia to my 14-year-old
sister okay good and she asked me if IND
and China go to war any day on what side
on whose side will Russia be and why
Russia every nation in geopolitics
follows is O its own interests its own
National interest there are no
friendships in
geopolitics no friendships there is no
emotions in geopolitics it's just cold
hard
self-interest so if India and China go
to war Russia will ask itself how in
there's a war going on between two
Nations that are
positively aligned with me what's the
best possible outcome for me that's the
question Russia is going to ask itself
there's no friendship here okay there's
no friendship in
geopolitics so if India if India and
China go to war Russia will make a show
of being neutral Russia will say that we
are friends with both of you please
don't
fight do a ceasefire and then go to the
negotiating table and and do diplomatic
talks and and figure out you know
resolve your differences to that that's
what they will say that will be the
official position they will not support
India they will not support China but
from a deeper perspective they will want
uh neither China or India to suffer too
much damage because both nations are
important to Russia China is a long-term
threat and adversary for Russia India is
not a threat and India is more of a
long-term partner for Russia but they
don't want China to get hurt too much
also because China is their buw against
the US right right now primarily so
ideally Russia will want India and
Russia not India and China not to go to
war and if the Nations go to war then
Russia will want a very rapid
ceasefire and all in the long term
Russia wants India to do better than
China but they don't want China to get
destroyed in any way because China well
it is it is one of the major barriers
for Russia when it comes to
counterbalancing the West it's
complicated so if India and China go to
war Russia will not take any sides they
will urge both Nations to go to to do to
to agree to a seiz fire that's what they
will do all right geopolitics
101 okay let's let's see some other
questions I can see lots of
questions uh OAS says I've seen lots of
people on Twitter mostly Christians and
Muslims okay if you say so that
propagate the Flat Earth theory is there
any single scientific fact that suggest
the Earth is flat there is no scientific
fact scientific fact that suggests the
Earth is flat that's your
straightforward answer the Earth is not
flat okay so let people believe whatever
they want that doesn't concern us does
it there is absolutely zero evidence
that that suggests that the Earth is
flat all the actual hard scientific
evidence demonstrates that the Earth is
roughly
spherical
okay uh
peush says can you update on the aeran
Armenia War there's not a war going on
there isn't a war going on right now
there is significant uh hostility on
both sides but right now there's no War
uh aeran has gobbled up plenty of
Armenian territory but right now there's
no war so that's the update but in the
long run run I sure that Russia and uh
I'm sorry not Russia Armenia I'm sorry
turkey and aeran will want to wipe AR
Armenia off the map of the Earth in case
some of you don't know where the these
nations are let me rapidly quickly show
it where this region is it is the
Caucasus region you know where India is
go westwards cross go past Iran and then
you have the Caucasus region between the
Black Sea and the Caspian Sea this
region and then you have these two
Nations here of Armenia and
aeran so east of Armenia you have aeran
west of Armenia you have what is now
called turkey turkey
okay and aeran is an ally of turkey you
could say it's a proxy of
turkey and uh aeran has gobbled up
plenty of Armenian territory in in
recent
years and uh in the long run turkey
would like Armenia to stop existing so
that it can
connect uh it can get a direct
connection with aeran and Nations like
turkistan etc etc which are all turkic
nations so that's the deal right now
there's no war going on but that is the
over objective of turkey and aeran to
wipe Armenia off the map of the world
and finish what they could not complete
a 100 years
ago the Armenian Genocide I know the
Turks won't like me saying it but it is
a fact they did conduct a series of
genocides which collectively is called
The Armenian Genocide beginning in the
last quarter of the 19 century and
ending before around 1920 or so the
major last wave was 1915 or
thereabouts okay what else do we have
um okay this is a hypothetical question
listen my opinion doesn't make any
difference in the world chirag says do
you believe Alexander the Greek would
have conquered more land and territory
than chingus Khan if he had lived into
his 70s or 80s like some of his generals
none of his generals conquered that much
territory his greatest General was ccas
nikator who carved out a decent Empire
with the help of the of India with the
help of our emperor Chandra gupt Maia
but even the greatest of Alexander's
generals did not carve out a major
gigantic Empire nothing compared to that
of JIS Khan if Alexander would have
lived into into his 70s or 80s I don't
know what he would have done listen it's
all
hypothetical it's all hypothetical I
think he pushed everything to to its
limits he out overed himself and he
reached a breaking point where his his
own generals his own soldiers Mutiny
against him they did not hate him they
did not dislike him but they knew that
what he was pushing for was impossible
it would be suicidal Alexander wanted to
go further west eastwards into India and
find the and fight the nandha Empire
that was nothing but suicide he would
have been squashed like a little insect
like a mosquito and his soldiers knew it
so they mutin they refused to go further
and then Alexander had no choice but to
retreat back to Babylon where he died of
whatever reason either alcoholism or the
wounds he suffered in India or poisoning
or malaria or whatever doesn't matter so
he had reached his limits there was
nothing who could do beyond that let's
say he had gone back to Greece and
recovered and then mounted a new
Invasion with the hope of reaching India
once again he would have to travel
thousands of kilometers and by that time
he would again be overstretched because
of the technological and other
limitations so Alexander was no chingis
Khan jingis was greater so I I my
opinion is that Alexander was not as
great as chingis Khan and no matter how
long he would have lived he would not
have succeeded in doing what chingis
Khan did okay so that's how I see it but
it's all hypothetical it's what would
have happened if this or that there's a
million parameters there's a million
factors that you to consider and so it's
it's all an exercise in in theoretical
hypotheticals and that's actually
pointless
okay
um simple L says what are your views on
libertarianism I myself consider I
consider myself one there are no
political parties in India that
represent libertarian values can it
exist in the future if the if then if
yes then how I don't know what
libertarianism is it means everybody
should have the maximum Freedom possible
in life and all that's ET Etc I believe
that's probably what libertarianism is
look when I was what 18 1920 I probably
would have been what you call a
Libertarian everybody should be free to
do whatever they want and uh so on so
forth and I always saw myself as a
liberal then I grew up and I realized
that what the actual definition of
liberal is something opposite and anthe
antical to what I see myself is so I've
always been somebody who likes you know
diversity let's say I mean when I was a
when I was a student I I lived in a
hostel and we had students from all
across India and other countries as well
and I really enjoyed that I liked
meeting people from different parts of
India different parts of the world
people who spoke different languages
people who had different backgrounds
Customs I liked it I found that
environment stimulating but there are
lots of people who want to be with
sameness they want to be people from the
same part of the world who speak the
same language and everything is just
safe and similar so I'm not that I like
the
diversity okay and and I I I like it so
um so I was like that but U so I've
considered myself a liberal always but
as I grew up I found that those who
consider who call themselves liberal
like in the political sense they are
actually the most hateful and intolerant
ones um but when it comes to
libertarianism I think it's taking that
to the extreme that uh people should
have
all the freedoms in the world and every
right that you can imagine democracy
obviously we want that but with rights
and with with uh privileges you should
also have duties right to society to
your country and Etc so I don't
know I I have nothing against
libertarianism everybody should get
rights everybody should get privileges
if you are a citizen of a certain
country you should get the Privileges
that come with that Etc but you should
also have something that counterbalances
it so if you have rights you also should
have duties and there are some people
who want all the rights in the world
don't want any duties so I'm not sure
what the spe exact definition of
libertarianism is I believe that there
should be a balance in life which is
something that I have come to understand
and and believe after a certain amount
of years on the planet initially I was
like all duty all rights should be given
to people and all that and I still
believe that people should have all all
rights and all freedoms that come with
democracy but you should also have
duties that's how I see it I don't know
about political parties in India that
represent libertarian values I I guess
none of them does um there are lots of
political parties that call themselves
liberal parties but those well what can
I say about that uh so that is how I see
it
sir ronit says who is behind the
terrorist attack in Russia is Israel
behind it which terrorist attack there
have been a series of terrorist attacks
are you talking about the theater
bombing or whatever it was the shooting
uh the Russians have made if you're
talking about that where a bunch of
tajic terrorists were
captured well initially the Russians
were saying that maybe the ukrainians
are behind it because they were
apparently escaping to Ukraine after
that the Russians have clammed up they
have made no statements and there there
have been no
repercussions for Ukraine or anybody
else so I don't know what's behind it uh
obviously I'm not associated with the
investigation so I would not know what
is not out there in the public domain so
I don't know who's behind it the
Russians will have to eventually let the
world know if they want the world to
know and that's how I see
it okay Ayan Ali says I'm from Pakistan
and I want to understand the role of
Pakistan in future geopolitics if you
can please explain Pakistan Pakistan's
role okay look listen once again let me
uh repeat I have nothing against the
people of Pakistan they are just common
people Ordinary People but
okay you you have asked for it so I'll
give it to you straight okay no no sugar
coating uh once again before I say
anything I'll repeat I have nothing
against the people of Pakistan uh I want
them to have good lives prosperous lives
everything that every every human being
on the planet deserves now when it comes
to the nation of Pakistan the way I see
it I see Pakistan as an artificially
created Nation it was created by
Outsiders to serve their interests not
the interest of the people of either
Pakistan or India so before 47 we were
all one people all Indians right then
certain political uh parties and
ideologies were were supported by the
British to create uh divisions in India
and to partition India because those
that partitioning served their
geopolitical interests and I'll not go
into that because it'll take one hour to
explain but the British had their
geopolitical interests and partitioning
India suited those interests eventually
Britain by 1958 by by the time of the SE
crisis became a third rate geopolitical
power and the center of power was was
transferred from London to Washington so
Pakistan ended up serving Washington's
geopolitical interests but until the
1980s Pakistan was not important until
1978 79 then the USSR invaded
Afghanistan and then it Pakistan became
important from the American perspective
and Z hak took full advantage of that
and the Americans funneled in poured in
tremendous amounts of cash and arms and
ammunition and Military experts into
Pakistan to train the mujahedin to fight
the Soviets in Afghanistan then the
Soviets leave by the late 1980s what 88
or something the Soviets leave
Afghanistan and then what do you do with
this excess capacity all those Fighters
the mujahidin all that armed arms
ammunition so the Americans said okay
let's funel it into India so Pakistan
acted as a proxy of the Americans and
they were already you know creating
trouble in India by the 1980s in Punjab
so the Pakistani is fought a proxy war
in Punjab first in India and then in
Kashmir okay the Pakistani army not the
people okay and Pakistan itself was the
proxy of the US because India was
aligned with the USSR during the Cold
War so the Americans wanted to punish
India and teach you know Heap some pain
on India so that is what Pakistan what
Pakistan's role has been from the
American perspective from from the
American perspective it's all about
balance of power in various parts of the
world so if India gets too big for its
boots we'll use Pakistan to to cut India
down to size that was the thinking after
Mr Modi came to power
2014 he had a whole different policy
against Pakistan and we know what
happened the balakot thing and the
surgical strikes and also Pakistan had
has been reigned in and India has now
adopted a policy of completely ignoring
Pakistan from a government perspective
uh and there's no trade with Pakistan
the Pakistani started dat okay they they
they cut off trade with India after
after 2019 and then India is now saying
we have no interest in trade with
Pakistan so that is the thing so that
has been the history now India is
completely ignoring Pakistan we want
nothing to do with Pakistan Sark is dead
from as far as we are concerned we will
work with other nations in the region in
the subcontinent through bilateral means
but we will not do anything which
involves Pakistan that is India's
perspective know I think it's the right
right perspective because Pakistan has
been the epicenter of global terrorism
and India Pakistan has been bleeding
India for decades with America's help
America has funded and financed
Pakistani terrorism in India that's the
thing now in the future how do I see it
well I have been very blunt about this I
see Pakistan is a is a temporary Nation
Pakistan will continue to exist as long
as America sees some utility for
Pakistan and China sees some utility for
utility for Pakistan but once America
feels that Pakistan has no no value
anymore for us I think Pakistan could
break up because there are too many C
centrifugal forces within within
Pakistan which are pulling it in
different directions there is the
balistan issue baloi people are not
happy with the Pakistan Army the way
they are treating treating the baluchi
pis the kar pakun they want to reunite
with Afghanistan with good reason then
there is Sy GSN has been going on for
such a long time and so on there are so
many of these factors in Pakistan that
will pull Pakistan in different
directions so Pakistan is an artificial
temporary nation that continues to exist
with external help uh the people of
India had never voted for Pakistan
whether it is the Hindus or the Muslims
okay and whatever election happened was
under foreign occupation which means it
is not a free and fair and legitimate
election if Hitler conducted an election
in France during his occupation of
France would you call it a free and fair
election it's not a free and fair
election similarly the elections that
the British conducted Ed in India in the
1940s or whever they were under foreign
occupation these are not free and fair
elections and that those those elections
were were then construed later on as a
referendum for Pakistan who are there to
decide that India should have been given
Independence and then we could have had
our own referendums but that's not how
it happened so the way I see it it's an
artificial temporary Nation it will at
some point in the future break up I hope
it happens I don't want India and
Pakistan to go to war I don't want
anything bad to happen to the people of
Pakistan but Pakistan has been bleeding
India for decades I don't see a good
future for it in geopolitics uh that's
just how I see it okay if it hurts your
feelings or anybody's feelings I don't
mean to but this is just how I see it
and I I'm talking just logically I'm not
talking emotionally okay so that's how I
see it I I wish you your family your
people the best you used to be part of
us but today you you are a foreign
nation and you have been bleeding us so
you can't expect us to have all good
feelings for you I still will I I
separate emotions from and from logic so
I I hope that there is that the people
of Pakistan have a have a good future
your people your future
Generations uh but I don't see a good
future for Pakistan in the long okay
sorry if if it hurts you but it's just
the way I see
it okay um
okay another geopolitics question by
pram is it strategically beneficial for
the US to Grant statehood to Guam
considering its existing alliances with
Japan and South Korea as counterbalances
to China in the region I would say the
Americans will never give statehood to
Guam because Guam is extremely important
for America now let's talk about where
Guam is in case most of us most of the
viewers don't know so let's go to the
map where's the map here's the map let's
find Guam so now for a change we go
eastwards from India from the
subcontinent region east east east and
we come into the North Pacific okay and
from North Pacific we're going to search
for Guam and here we have Guam east of
the Philippines it is you could say in
the Philippine Sea south of the Northern
Mariana Islands this is Guam now let's
take a deeper look at
Guam
okay
um this is Guam and you can see that
there are at least three
airports on Guam there's one here
there's another one here there's a third
one here this may not be that active or
operational but that there you have it
and you will see a very good Naval
facility here okay a very very strong
robust Naval facility US Coast Guard
forces etc etc and there's another one I
expect in the
South so there is something here but it
is not not that much of a naval
base so Guam is a military stronghold
okay of the United States it is a a
vital Cog in the US power projection
capabilities and the US ability to
encircle China from a
distance so there are two or three there
are three Island chains that we speak
about and Guam is part of the second
island chain which includes the northern
Marian Islands etc
etc so the question is should the us
give stra statehood to Guam make Guam
independent is it strategically
beneficial to the US and the answer is
straightforward it is not strategically
beneficial for the US to relinquish any
kind of control over Guam okay Guam is
extremely important for the us they can
deploy okay let's let's once again take
a look at look at what assets they have
deployed here let's take a look at what
what could be here at the
airport okay this is uh could this could
this be a civilian airliner maybe not uh
there could be obviously some civilian
planes etc etc over here maybe this is a
civilian airport what do we have here we
have
certain assets that I can see from high
on Top This doesn't look very
military okay so that's one airport
let's take a look at the other one Okay
this may be more
interesting so the us obviously can land
any kind of aircraft here including
extreme long distance extremely heavy
strategic bombers now this obviously is
where you would deploy fighter planes
you don't see them here because those
could be hidden away
somewhere perhaps these look like nice
little
hangers there's not not a lot of
Hardware visible here is there maybe a
little bit this looks like one of those
military planes yeah it's
gray uh what else do we
have what else do we have okay it's all
nicely okay you can see some more
military assets these are heavy duty
bombers obviously strategic
aircraft uh I'm sure if I spend more
time digging in digging deep I'll find
more stuff but okay let's not do that
the point is Guam is extremely extremely
important it can the US can deploy any
kind of aircraft over here including
extremely long distance long range and
very heavy strategic bombers and whatnot
fighter planes Etc they have a very good
Naval facility there so the US can have
aircraft carriers and submarines coming
in there why would the US give that away
why why why why why it's like the
Americans giving up Diego Garcia in the
Indian Ocean region from which they can
project power over India and the whole
region why would they give it away why
the Americans acquired Diego Garcia I'll
not show it on the map right now you can
look it up it's south of India south of
the Maldives Diego Garcia they acquired
Diego Garcia from the
British in 1973 what happened two years
before 1973 71 happened and India broke
Pakistan into two right in
1971 and the Americans were powerless to
stop that they tried they sent uh an
entire aircraft carrier strike task
force strike group and the British also
sent their aircraft carrier and still
they were not able to prevent India from
breaking Pakistan and liberating
Bangladesh so that's why they acquired
Diego Garcia to stop such a thing from
happening in the future
so in the future I don't want it to
happen but if there's a war between
India and Pakistan the Americans could
project power on India from Theo Garcia
so why would you give that up why makes
no sense you keep that with you so the
answer is no it's not strategically
beneficial for them to do
that um historical Marvel says do you
think we should have direct prime
minister elections your opinion on the
current American president okay let's
take one question like you have three
question questions in one should we have
direct prime minister election you're
talking about so you should not call
that a prime minister election then you
should call it a presidential election
because it's only in the presidential
system worldwide that you have direct
elections for the person who will be the
leader in any Prime ministerial system
which is a Westminister system you have
indirect elections you you you can only
vote for your local MP and then the MPS
of the largest party will then get
together together and decide the Prime
Minister I think it takes power away
from the people why do you want to keep
this such things indirect this system
the Westminster system evolved on a
small insignificant island in the in the
Atlantic Ocean called Britain why do we
want to follow that that is completely
inappropriate for a gigantic
subcontinent sized Nation like India why
do we slavishly ape their inferior
system a large Nation like India a
gigantic Nation like India needs a more
direct system of governance and and of
Elections I think we should have a
presidential system I completely in
favor of at least a presidential system
if not something even more
robust so I believe we should have that
the people should have the right to
directly vote for the leader they they
think should rule the country or or
administer the country for so and so
years so yeah that's what I believe
um Samar Gandhi says if even if we are
able to understand and develop cryogenic
sleeping want bone mass still decrease
in space yeah if you are in space in
micro gravity or zero gravity conditions
your bone mass bone density everything
will will decrease whether you are
asleep even if you're asleep in let's
say cryogenic sleep uh okay what is
cryogenic sleep it means that you reduce
the temperature of the body to as close
to zero as POS possible so that
everything slows down all the biological
processes slow down but you don't freeze
the body so uh what's the what's the
freezing point of water is zero right
but the anomalous expansion of water
happens up to what two degrees 3 degrees
so I think you want to keep the
temperature as close to zero as possible
without having ice crystals forming in
the blood which will puncture all the
cell walls and and Destroy DNA and
whatnot so maybe you keep the
temperature to four or five degrees or
something like that so it will reduce
the rate the speed of the biological
processes but not entirely stop it but
will it cause death because if a body is
at three at 5° Centigrade it's it's
like under normal circumstances you
would die but let's say you were able to
do that so it will slow down the
biological processes but not entirely
stop them which means that the bones and
everything will keep on functioning in
some way at a very slow speed very low
rate which could still over time if it's
a kic sleep for let's say 20 years it
could still end up decreasing your bone
density and all that so yeah that's a
problem we have to eventually address if
we are even even if we are able to to
develop cryogenic sleep because reduced
bone density Etc will lead to all kinds
of complications it could lead to a very
high incidence of just stress fractures
or whatever which is terrible which is
terrible you don't want that so yeah I
agree with you it will still cause
problems
pruma says is it possible to change our
military Doctrine from no first attack
policy to attack when we feel endangered
is this is it possible to apply this for
nukes as well
look it's our choice What doctrine we
want I'm not sure we have a military
doctrine that says we will not attack
first we certainly have a no first use
policy
officially for nuclear weapons that we
will not use nuclear weapons unless we
are first attacked with nuclear weapons
so we will not be the first to attack
ever but we will we reserve the right to
respond with nukes if we are if if we
suffer a nuclear attack when it comes to
non-nuclear military means I don't think
we have a no first attack policy and we
should not I I believe that even when it
comes to nukes we should do away with
the no first use policy or look I think
there a like I always say there's a huge
huge difference between words and
actions you can say something in words
we believe in peace we believe in
nonviolence we believe in human rights
blah blah blah which the Americans do
all the time but look at their actions
how different they are they are the
worst of the warmongers the Americans
aren't they so they talk about peace
they talk about human rights they talk
about democracy but they are the first
to endanger peace to violate peace terms
they're the first to commit human rights
violations they the they are the they
the they have they have a track record
of supporting and installing
dictatorships in Africa and other parts
of the world so their actions
are completely contrary to their stated
positions so when it comes to a nuclear
policy we can have a stated no first use
policy but in the future if we feel
threatened why should why why can we not
use nukes first so uh so there is you
know there is a
public set of pronouncements and there
something you will actually do so I
think it's okay to have a stated nuclear
no first use
policy and you don't have to adhere to
that in the real world so yeah but if
you actually are are planning to adhere
to a no first use policy I think that
would be really stupid so we know that
you
know um according to the UN conventions
Etc according to what they call
international law and all that uh new
what chemical weapons are prohibited
biological weapons are hited but we know
for a fact that all major powers are
developing all these weapons in the
stock piles of such weapons but
officially they'll say no no no we don't
believe in this so it's just like
that okay okay next
next Malik said says suggest some must
read books for 18 year to 22 year olds
listen I if you ask me about books I
will remember nothing have I've read so
many books in my life that nothing will
come to my mind I have I have a couple
of videos if you look at this channnel
you go to the videos and you look at the
oldest videos I think one of the first
couple of videos I made on this channel
in the very beginning was book
recommendations I'm sure there was a
book there's a book recommendation video
about history books I think and there
there's one about
physics but if you want in the future I
could
do I could I could make a video showing
the books I have here and then you can
pick and choose whatever you want I have
a tremendous amount of books
way more than the ones you see over here
so in the future I could do a bookshelf
tour I think people have been asking
that for years and I've not done that so
so I could do that but right now if you
ask me on the spot I'll remember nothing
I've read so many books that they've all
got mixed up in my head and I remember
next to nothing about that and uh I
never had the taste of a 18y old or 22
year old I even as a kid I used to read
books that adults read so so what I'll
do eventually in the next few weeks I
will do perhaps a bookshelf tour of the
books that I can show you not the books
I can't show you because I have some
classified books which I will not show
anyone but the ones I can show you I
will I will probably do a bookshelf tour
so please have some patience and
eventually I'll do
that because there are some books that
you can't show classified books if you
know what I
mean everybody should read classified
books from from time to time if you know
what those are uh okay Vijay says why do
you say China is a threat to Russia okay
you have you seen the news of late the
Chinese you know that they have been
renaming places in arunachal Pradesh to
Chinese names you know that they've been
doing that provocation for years you
know they take a bunch of I don't know
geographical places in arunachal Pradesh
and they give them Chinese names and
they include that region in their
map in in Chinese territory is Chinese
territory in their Maps they've been
doing that to India for a long time
recently India went ahead and renamed
some places in Tibet to Indian names now
the chines have done that to Russia
also in 2023 I believe they put out a
map in which many parts of Russia were
Chinese okay parts of Russia's Far
East so when it comes to uh you know
whether it is
uh I don't know what places they were
but I think
um somewhere near Vlad VTO is here and
so on they they renamed some of the
Russian places to Chinese
names so that is one thing so they are
they are reopening old territorial
disputes that they had with Russia and
then you must remember what happened in
the 1960s I think in 68 or 69 the usuri
river clashes which was almost War okay
the Chinese and Russians went to the
were battles that happened for the
control of an island in this region I
mean the Border here between China and
Russia there's a river that demarcates
the border and that river is called the
usuri river let's go deep down this is
the usuri river as you can see on the
screen and there were usuri River
clashes I think in ' 69 hundreds of
soldiers died on both sides and as a
consequence of these clashes Russia the
USSR had actually decided to Nuke China
to launch a nuclear attack on China it
was decided and the Americans came to
know about this and they they threatened
Russia with a counter attack nuclear
attack if the Russians attacked China
and that's why the Americans saved China
from being annihilated by
Russia so that's the history between
Russia and
China and if you look at Russia's
biggest neighbor with a common border it
is China and it's a border that
thousands of kilometers long
at least as long as the Indian border
with Tibet if not more definitely more I
think and there is a territorial dispute
there when two large powerful Nations
have a common border they can never be
friends that is an iron law of
geopolitics okay and if you want to know
why read history read history of the
past 2,000 3,000 years and you will see
that over and over again that is why
China is a threat to Russia China is
right now a much bigger economy it is
way larger than the Russian economy but
Russia is way more powerful than China
militarily and people will disagree well
those people they need to read a little
those of you who disagree oh China is a
superpower blah blah blah do you even
know what a superpower means China is
nothing near a superpower Russia is a
near superpower China is not but um it's
okay if someone wants to disagree watch
something else don't watch this channel
then so that's why why these are very
powerful Nations China is the much
larger economy Russia is the much larger
military overall in terms of hard power
Russia is way stronger than China but
China and China is laying claims to
Russian territory so don't you think
that's a threat for Russia so that's the
that's the reason why China is a threat
to Russia
okay v v V26 says do you think Hinduism
will spread more rapidly to Russia and
the US in the coming years no I don't
think so I think Russia I think Hinduism
could stop existing in India in the next
100 years if Hindus are not
careful okay look at the number of
religious buildings that are coming up
in India what are the major religions in
India today Hinduism is the old religion
yes then you have Islam and then you
have
Christianity these are the two other
main religions in India apart from
Hinduism apart from the dharmic
religions now look look at in the in the
past 10 years which religious structures
are cropping up over India do you see
new new Hindu temples being being
constructed no but when it comes to the
other two abrahamic religions you will
see lots and lots of new structures
coming up all over the place which means
these religions have all the money and
they are building see I am not saying I
have anything against X religion or Y
religion I'm just telling you what's
happening these religions their
religious structures are coming up
everywhere how many temples are coming
up Hindu temples next to Nan so I think
forget about other countries Hinduism
will cease to exist in the next 550 to
200 years in India itself and you people
are just sitting and all happy and all
complacent and this is such such
processes have happened in the past in
other
civilizations look at where Indonesia is
today look at where Egypt is today look
at where Europe is today you think
Christianity is a European religion
really you think so look at what person
is today so India could go down the road
soon enough so forget about Hinduism
spreading outside India I think Hinduism
if if India is not careful will cease to
exist in India itself and the government
of India is doing nothing about
that which is
disappointing
um brid say how big was the hastinapur
Empire how do you know hastinapur was an
Empire what is hastinapur Empire
hastinapur was a
city it was not an
Empire so yeah look we talking about the
Mahabharat era here
right uh it's it's hard to say how big
which kingdom which empire was there was
no Empire as such in India at the time
um there were many kingdoms and we know
when the war happened the kurukshetra
war when it happened you had two
alliances the corova Le Alliance and the
panda Le Alliance lots of other kings
from other places came and fought on
both sides so even the kavas and the
pandas were not the rulers of Empires
they were rulers of
Kingdoms but that
war it shaped the the future history of
India which we are living in to some
extent so hastinapur was a kingdom it
was not an Empire I think it was the
capital of the kingdom and as and it was
not very big as far as I know obviously
we don't have sufficient information to
delineate the boundaries and all that uh
but there is plenty information
reasonable reasonably good amount of
information in the maharat the maharat
talks about so many geographical
landmarks regions Rivers uh pilgrimage
places TS it talks about pilgrimages it
talks about migrations it talks about
voyages it talks about hundreds of
Kingdoms and cities and towns it talks
about forests and so much more so it's
it's a treasure Trove of GE geographic
information so I don't recall right now
how large was the Kingdom that was
centered around hastinapur but if you're
interested read up the Mahabharat the
the full text not the Abed versions of
whatever all
right
um okay physics Vishnu says two
questions firstly is the singularity at
the center of a black hole the same as
the point before the Big Bang if not how
are they different look we don't know
what was there the at the moment of the
Big Bang according to to some versions
of how we see things there could have
been a
singularity a point like Singularity of
infinite density infinite curvature
infinite energy and mass density Etc
that's one possibility but singularities
are actually non-physical because they
are where mathematics breaks
down um so the singularity at the heart
of a black hole which arises as a
consequence of the solutions of
Einstein's field equations of general
relativity those singularities actually
are telling us that your field equations
are actually not entirely correct they
need some modification maybe at the
quantum scale okay so maybe even at the
heart of a black hole at the center of a
black hole you may not have
singularities singularities are
non-physical Singularity means you're
dividing by zero that's why it's
throwing up
Infinities so most
likely there may not be a singularity
even at the center of black holes and
then if singularities are physical then
maybe even at the instant where the big
bang happened maybe it was not a
singularity maybe it was somewhere else
something else and there are theories
like Loop quantum gravity that tell you
that the smallest volume that is
physically possible is of the order of
about 10 rais to- 97
M which is the which is shockingly
ridiculously small that's that's the
cube of the plank length roughly uh yeah
so according to Loop quantum gravity
there was no Singularity and that was
the smallest area volume possible
there's a big bounce or something like
that so the question you're answering
there's no real answer to that because
we don't have sufficient information we
don't have sufficient information about
the moments right after the big bang and
we don't have sufficient information
about what is what lies at the center of
black holes because the black hole any
black hole is shrouded by this
mysterious thing called an event horizon
and we we can't look beyond that inside
a black hole otherwise we would know
what the internal structure of black
holes is like right now we don't know
what's inside a black
hole there could be a singularity there
could be strings there could be
something else there could be a gas
there could be who knows an entire
universe inside or something so we don't
have the answers to these questions and
that's why physics is so interesting and
it's so important and there's so much
more research that needs to be done in
physics so much more progress that's
possible in physics that's why physics
is fascinating these are the Deep
profound questions that that keep
physicists interested Big M Mysteries
gigantic Mysteries it's like a detective
search you know a detective Quest there
are some Clues vague Clues here and
there and we're trying to piece them
together and figure out what what is the
solution so yes you ask any physicist of
reasonable intelligence he or she will
tell you we don't know the answers to
these
questions but that's what makes it
interesting all
right d says why is Saudi Arabia
investing so much in sports they are
spending millions of dollars in football
boxing golf Etc people says it's Sport
washing what is this look once you are
prosperous you want to increase your
nation's Prestige and one of the best
ways to increase your nation's Prestige
Worldwide is to have excellence in
competitions with other nations and a
typical example of compet competitions
between nations is sports why did the
USSR invest so much in sporting
Excellence the USSR was sporting
superpower why did East Germany spend so
much in its sporting programs why is
China Investing so much in sports
because these nations understand that it
it is important not just to be
prosperous and all that but you know
International Prestige is also very
important and that is something India's
politicians lack India's politicians
care nothing about India's Prestige I'm
not talking about the current crop of
politicians I'm talking about
historically the Indian governments have
completely neglected Sports we say that
hockey is our national sport well what
have we done about
hockey what about football the most
popular sport in the world what have we
done about football we have an Indian
what sport we have an Indian football
league right which runs for a month or
two very low
quality why can't we have the the
equivalent of the English Premier League
in India for football why can't we have
that why is that not happening because
Indians simply don't care the people
want that the people want sportic
Excellence but the people with the power
and the money they simply don't
care and when it comes to hockey why
don't we have a hockey league like the
IPL why not and why is the IPL something
that runs only for two months like like
a small carnival a proper serious sports
League should run for eight or nine
months and then you should have a three
Monon off season that's how a serious
sport Sports League
runs and when it comes to Cricket for
example why don't we have an IPL that
lasts eight or nine months and you could
even have one odas in that or something
I'm sure it will capture the imagination
of the public I mean if you have the
eepl English Premier League of football
that runs for eight or nine months and
it's the most watched league in the
world why can't we replicate the same
for football for Cricket for hockey and
other sports in India
and imagine how much employment it will
generate imagine that it's great for the
economy you'll have more stadiums you
will need so many more coaches you will
need medical professionals you need
trainers you will need people who are
will take care of the Lawns and stuff
and you will need so much more Sporting
Goods you will need manufacturing
imagine it will it can run an entire
economic
ecosystem these are so these are the
benefits The non- Prestige benefits of
of sporting Excellence of having an
entire EOS system of sports of various
Sports whether it is mixed martial arts
boxing kabudi why not why not turn kabi
kabudi into a worldwide phenomenon why
not why is there no such ambition in
India why are people in India so
unambitious I just don't get it why
don't we want we aim to be the best in
the world in sports we have 1.4 billion
people we have people of all kinds of
genetics and abilities we will beat
everybody in the world we'll even beat
we will wipe the floor with China
we you know the average Indian is
physically superior to the average
Chinese the Chinese are winning gold
medals all over the place imagine if you
Empower Indians what they will do we we
have the potential to be a sporting
superpower to be the number one sporting
superpower greater than all the European
Western Nations and and greater than
China we have the potential we don't do
it Saudi Arabia understands this that's
why they're investing in sports they're
importing athletes from the African
nations you know Muslim athletes from
from the African nations so if you look
at the just not just Saudi Saudi Arabia
even the other Arabic countries like
Oman Etc if you look at their sporting
teams in the Asian Games or Olympics or
whatever most of their athletes are of
African origin they're Muslims or they
convert to Islam and they represent
these countries because these countries
want the prestige they want and you know
when you travel abroad if you are from a
nation who which produces great athletes
that are admired worldwide you are
respect
it's it's sad that India's leaders
historically have not cared in an Iota
for India's Prestige and the kind of
respect that the nation should should
have
globally so yeah football boxing golf
whatever track and field Athletics Etc
rich countries will spend on it India
has the resources to do that but we're
not doing it whatever sporting success
is happening is happening through the
through the sacrifice and the hard work
put in by individual Cath and their
families you see that's what's happening
it is it is it is so
unfortunate we don't have these great
big sports leagues we have the in the
money we have everything we need to
create these sporting leagues but we
don't do that why don't we have a sports
League like the IPL for hockey cricket
cricket um and so much more we should do
that we don't do it so that's why Saudi
Aria is doing it
Shivam Singh says why have many Indians
stopped wearing turbin what cultural
social or practical factors have
contributed to this change the reason
why Indians have stopped wearing the
traditional Indian clothes is because we
are all brainwashed and we think that is
inferior there was a time when those big
mustaches were the sign of royalty do
you remember that you may not remember
it because none of us was alive at the
time there was a time before the
Europeans intruded into our land when
big
mustaches and big beards were the sign
of
royalty but today you know what the
British did they turned that into the
sign of a doorman so if you go to any
festar hotel today the darwal the door
man will have a huge big mustache which
was once the the symbol of royalty the
Europeans took everything that was great
all the symbolism that was great about
India and they turned it into the Sy
symbolism of something inferior because
we Indians we see doormen as inferior
right somebody who stands at the door
all day and opens doors for people
obviously it's kind of menial labor so
the British did that and today we see
everything through foreign eyes because
we are so brainwashed it's not our fault
it's not the fault of today's kids that
they are brainwashed like that because
the education system has brainwashed
them so once again it goes back to the
education system I've spoken enough that
about that so I'll not speak about it so
because of this of this colonial
brainwashing we have stopped wearing
traditional clothing whether it is
turbans whether it is doties whether it
is saris or whatever even today it's
like you know ladies when they wear s
it's like a fancy dress thing but for
your day-to-day life you don't wear that
uh and I don't blame people for that
because European clothes are are
probably more convenient life is so much
faster more hectic today you want to
just throw something on and get out of
the house and go work go slave away for
12 hours right for somebody make
somebody make your company rich while
you slave away so uh that's how it is
so so on the one hand you see it as
something inferior something traditional
reserved for fancy dress occasions and
secondly it is not as convenient in the
past life was more leisurely you did not
India was a Land of Plenty India was a
land of prosperity so you don't have did
not have to slave for 12 hours a day
working for somebody everybody had their
own profession India was a totally
different society which is not described
to us in our textbooks what was daily
life in India like a thousand years ago
before the foreign uh invasions and
occupation of India what was Indian
Society like a thousand years ago they
simply don't tell us they will only tell
you that you have a nation civilization
of inferior people of backward people so
that's why we see all everything that is
associated with Indian culture as
backward and that's why we don't want to
wear it so look at me I'm wearing
what this is foreign dress yeah but we
just use used to it
convenience all
right Lisa Rose says why have Indians
always not been United in history and
when the culture was so rich and
advanced and the people were very
intellectual considering their great
works and texts it's because of the size
of India I'll tell you what today we are
used to cell phones we used to this
instant communication I'm talking on on
air and you can watch this wherever you
are in the world in real time that did
not exist even a century ago that did
not exist even in
1990 and a 100 years ago there was no
telecommunication there was no radio no
telephone so it was
extremely difficult to administer a
large Kingdom forget about an Empire I
can't imagine how Chandra gupt Maia how
Ashok how
keska
Etc administered a gigantic Empire a
subcontinent sized Empire how did they
do it how do you control everything how
do you get reports about what's
happening takes a month to get a report
from gandhar if you're sitting in Parra
and yet you were able to do that so it
was very difficult it was only people of
immense cap capacity capability who
could administer an
Empire that's why it's been so rare in
India we have these Imperial Cycles you
have the great Moria Empire when you had
people of incredible Talent like Emperor
Ashok like chra Gupta Moria Etc who were
able to unify the whole subcontinent
then you have the kosan Empire someone
like kishka the great one of the
greatest Emperors we've had then you had
the great Gupta Empire who again unified
India then you had the cholas who
unified much of Southern India and the
whole of Southeast Asia incredible
imagine that imagine that and then you
had the marata Empire and obviously
there was a Kota Empire and I'm sure
I've missed one or two here but here or
there but you get it right so it was
incredibly difficult to coordinate
everything
it was much easier to to administer a
smaller
Kingdom okay so so there was no
telecommunications and all that and
that's the reason why big Empires always
break up rapidly look at the Mongol
Empire that sh Ching is concreted it was
half the known world of the time but
then it had to fragment because it was
impossible to to administer it from one
place without
telecommunications so because we did not
have the technology in those days no one
in the world had
that's why it was very rare for the
entire subcontinent to unite despite
having the same culture the same
religion the same intellectual
advancements science mathematics Etc but
we do not have telecommunications
electricity all that that's why India
was
typically uh an a civilization of
multiple kingdoms and only once in a
while was it Consolidated into a single
Empire okay it's because of the
technological limitations we had at the
time so if the if the emperor wants to
visit if the emperor is sitting in
patliputra and he says that I want to go
to uh what's the city pavati Peshawar
purpur whatever or I want to go to
kapisa Kabul or I want to go to
somewhere in Southern India it would
take him two months to get there today
the Prime Minister can just hop into a
plane and in 3 hours is there in the
past it would take two months three
months that's how difficult it was so
these are the reasons why it Al so hard
to unify the entire
subcontinent jph P
says when a person is born to the time
to die life is filled with violence
Bloodshed competition for scar resources
and fighting for survival life at the
prim primordial level is cruel and
barbaric look that's one view of life
that is the Buddhist view of life I
would say goam Buddha said life is D
life is sadness and pain and
suffering and the objective of life
should be to attain MOA should be to
attain Nirvana Liberation so that's one
way of looking at life of course if you
look at look back at your life there
will be plenty of instances where there
was unhappiness there was
sadness everybody in everyone's if your
life is long enough you will Multi you
will witness multiple tragedies
tragedies whether you want it or not
it's going to happen so yes that is
simply the nature of life every person
who has ever lived on this planet has
gone through that cycle but it is what
it is you can look at it pessimistically
or you can look at it positively like
that's just the way it is we are here
for a certain amount of time either you
spend your life trying to escape if you
either you spend your life seeing it as
a very negative thing full full of
misery or you take it in your stride and
try to be happy every instant of your
life and work towards creating something
it's entirely up to you so I am a very
posit positive optimistic person okay I
think life has light as well as dark
life has happiness as well as sadness
life has Beauty as well as ugliness and
if you are unfortunate enough to be born
in certain parts of the world there's
there's all that that you're mentioning
violence Bloodshed competition for scar
resources fly fighting for survival in
India it's not the
case increasingly so if you're talking
about the 1970s 1980s if you're talking
about the British occupation of India
the European occupation of India if
you're talking about the turkic
occupation of India yes daily violence
Bloodshed competition blah blah blah so
we are now actually in a good place in
India at least I'm not sure where JF is
from looks like Italy but if you're from
Italy well you don't have
that so uh some of us are fortunate
enough to be born in a good time or
maybe in a good place and some of us are
not so fortunate and in in that case you
have this things so look there's nothing
you can do about where you're born when
you are born and the specific
circumstances of the of your life that
begin at time t equal to zero in physics
there's nothing you can do about it all
you can do is about what you do with
what has been given to
you and you can look at it positively or
negatively I choose to look at it
positively so that's just the way I see
it
okay um
potato praiser says what's your opinion
on YouTubers running for prime minister
in the UK will content creators take
over in the future I am not aware of
that which Youtuber is running from
prime minister in the UK I think
everybody has the right to stand for
elections um when it comes to content
creators well there are different kinds
of content
creators uh some content creators could
be very serious content creators some
could be entertainers some could be
Educators some could be creating content
to bring awareness to their business or
to whatever cause they're working on and
so many different
things so I don't know if content
creators will take over in the future I
don't want entertainers should take over
in the future entertainers should never
be taken seriously their job is to
pretend to be something they are not and
we know what Shri vishnugupta chakas
where is the book somewhere here arastra
what he said about entertainers he said
entertainers should should be taxed
heavily and kept far away from
society pay them well tax them heavily
and keep them away from society
entertainers should never be role models
and look at today's India we are doing
the exact opposite of what the great
chanakya said we are idolizing
entertainers entertainers are
entertainers their job is to pretend to
be something they are not how do you
know that they're not pretending at any
given point in time it is their
profession pretending it's what they are
best at so my point my point is
entertainers should never be taken
seriously as politicians or as Leaders
today we have okay listen I have nothing
against any specific person but you have
more of this happening entertainers
getting into
politics that is I think something that
the great three vishnugupta chanak would
have frowned upon and he would be very
disappointed with the way we are living
our lives today okay with the standards
we have set for ourselves today we have
really lowered the standards if he were
to see today's India would be very
disappointed with the population with
the Common Man Woman child and also with
the
leaders so uh but when it comes to
content creators well if they are
intellectuals if they are if they have
any traits of leadership Etc why not
that's
okay okay s says what's the origin of
algebra Indian or Arab algebra is an
Arabic translation of something that
came out of Sanskrit the origin of
algebra is Indian as simple as that the
Arabs did a great job translating it for
their own benefit and then those
translations made their way into Europe
and now the Europeans want to credit
everything to the Arabs or to the Greeks
or to somebody else but never India the
origin of algebra is Indian not Arabic
and the Arab translators themselves made
it very
clear alind or whatever the the name of
the book was they had multiple books
that in the title itself credited India
so these were translations from Sanskrit
into Arabic and then into Persian
whatever else so the origin of algebra
is 100%
Indian Samar arara says no disrespect to
cret Cricket by why aren't other sports
promoted in India I don't know I would
like to see other sports promoted I
really enjoy hockey I enjoy martial arts
boxing wrestling all that stuff I enjoy
shot put I enjoy javelin throw I enjoy
sprinting or whatever track and field I
would like to watch rugby why not rugby
why not
swimming I I would love like I love
sports I would like to see all sports
why not tennis table tennis badminton
okay badminton is doing reasonably well
in India these days because um you know
nothing succeeds like success we had sa
Nal who started succeeding and then you
had uh CNU P synu great girl who's doing
tremendous tremendous work in know in
her field uh pranit and some other
players so we're doing well in badminton
we're doing reasonbly in table tennis
and there's so much more we can do yeah
so I also no disrespect to Cricket but
but I completely agree with you why
aren't the sports promoted in India
because I I don't know why I don't know
why we have the ability to play the
sports why isn't football promoted in
India football could take off and become
a gigantic phenomenon in India so could
hockey if you have the same eepl format
not the IPL format but the EPL format so
yeah I would like to see it I don't I
don't know
why mlav says have you watched chandu
Champion that movie says a lot about
rotten system I have not even heard of
it but okay if it's a good movie I would
say let people watch it I I kind of have
given up on Bollywood and OT series and
all that I don't watch any a single
Hindi Serial of any kind I don't watch
Hindi movies
anymore except for the very rare
occasion where I will watch something
but yeah so I don't know what's going on
who are the current actors actresses
Stars superstars no idea I don't watch
it but okay if it's a good movie thank
you for the
recommendation rth says why did the
Mongols under stre chingis Khan invade
Japan in the year 1274 there's a video
game based on this event in history okay
let me show you
something okay to to answer this
question here we have Google okay our
best friend is
Google the JIS Khan
we'll search for chingis Khan go to
Wikipedia which year does the great man
die
1227 and you can look it up on
encyclopedia BR britanica or wherever
else you want he dies in the year 1227
and yet people said that he tried to
invade
Japan why why can't you do a simple
Google
search I don't get
it so my what I keep saying in every
episode is please raise your standards
why do you need to be
spoonfed please do a little bit of due
diligence when did chingis Khan when was
he born when did he die that much at
least you can look at right that much
just a simple Google search and then
which year do the Mongols in Japan 1274
which
is about 50 years half a century after
he dies and yet most people come to me
and say that oh chingis Khan you said
that chingis Khan did not lose a single
military campaign what about Japan he he
he lost to the Japanese are you kidding
me it was kubl Khan chingis Khan's
grandson who launched two attempts to
invade
Japan so why did kubl Khan did that
maybe he wanted to expand his Empire it
wasn't chingis Khan who did that it was
kubl Khan who did that he also tried
something in Southeast Asia which also
failed kubl Khan was no chingis Khan
okay there you have
it uh Nagal lakmi says why are North
American humans animals insects bigger
and stronger than Indians
what okay well the North American humans
they are the europan Invaders and
occupiers of America the descendants of
the colonialists the Europeans you know
they originated in the cold climate so
they had to be bigger larger all that
stuff um animals insects
I I don't
agree which uh North American animal is
larger than Indian animals the which is
the largest cat in North America it is
the the lynx the cougar the Puma they
are smaller than the biggest cats in
India the lion and the
tiger there you have it uh what else
dogs well their dogs are fluffier
because of the cold climate Etc what
else snakes I think we have larger
snakes in India than North America the
Indian various pythons are larger than
the North American the largest snakes in
North America what else do we have
rabbits listen so you can generalize I
just gave you an example the largest
North American cat is smaller than the
largest Indian
cats and uh so on humans the North
American humans are not even North
American they are descendants of
foreigners insects I don't know so you
can't generalize is is my point okay
um what else did they have they had
saber-tooth Tigers but those went
extinct a long time ago maybe the North
American bears are larger than the
Indian brown bears the Indian brown bear
and the North American grizzly bear are
actually the same
species but the subspecies are different
whatever you want to say so the Indian
one the Himalayan brown bear is somewhat
smaller than the North American Kodiak
grizzly or
whatever okay so it's one
example so my point is there is no
pattern as such that everything in North
America is larger it's it's not true
um Mr red bird says what's your opinion
on the disastrous American presidential
debate that happened a couple of nights
ago I wasn't able to watch it I was
traveling I still haven't seen the
debate I want to see the video of the
debate but I've seen the memes and it it
appears that Mr Biden malfunctioned a
few
times which is no big surprise and Mr
Trump at least once he had to say that I
could not understand what this guy was
saying yeah total disaster for for Mr
Biden the robot is malfunctioning well
what can you do uh even Obama had to
tweet something about that that that one
failed debate is not the end of the road
or something so even he had to admit
that Mr Biden failed and he lost the
debate so yeah I haven't seen it yet so
I can't really tell you any details
about how I see it but overall I'm not
surprised I'm surprised that they even
put Biden out there in the debate but
see the
Democrats have been pretending the past
four years that Biden is fit to be the
the president of the country when they
know he is not so they have been
gaslighting the people of America and
now when the debates are supposed to
happen if they pull him out then it is
an admission of guilt to the people of
North America for to the people of the
US that we have been lying to you all
this time so that's why they had to put
him and then the will use these
disastrous debates as the excuse to pull
him out I believe so I don't think Mr
Biden is going to be the final
presidential C candidate at some point
in time I believe he will be pulled out
and even Kamala Harris won't be a
presidential candidate I think it'll be
either Oprah Winfrey or Dwayne Johnson
or Hillary Clinton or m Michelle
Obama Michelle I think it'll be one of
those those probably Michelle Obama or
Hillary
or Oprah Winfrey or Dwayne Johnson or
some actor actress whatever typically
these people are proxies for somebody
else else else who really who holds the
real
power so my perspective is that Biden is
not going to be the real candidate when
it comes to the actual election at the
end of this
year rajit says how can bat stop
religious conversions that threaten our
indigenous culture as doing so will make
the government look look fascist
dictatorial and the whole whole
anti-india toolkit will get activated
what needs to happen is we need to get
so strong that others cannot interfere
in our Internal Affairs see what the
Chinese did to the Tibetans see what
they did to the UR did anybody dare
condemn China no everyone's quiet it's
because China is so much more powerful
and everybody needs the Chinese economy
on their side India is way weaker than
China it's not the fault of Mr Modi this
a fault of the previous governments in
the past 70 years Mr Modi is trying to
change it he needs to do better
obviously
but at least he's doing a lot he's doing
way more than anybody has done before
India needs to become a 105 trillion
economy then nobody will dare question
India but we are not even a $5 trillion
economy right now we have a long road
ahead of us so that's what needs to
happen if you want people to stop
meddling in your internal Affair you
need to get stronger you need to build
that muscle right now we don't have the
muscle we are the fourth larg fifth
largest economy whatever will soon be
the third largest economy I don't care
about that we have to hit the10 trillion
Mark then the $1 15 trillion Mark I
think India will be safe when we are
around the $15 trillion Mark in terms of
today's
dollars so right now we are weak and you
know what blinkin was saying recently
that India is religious freedoms are
under threaten in India and India is
trying to clamp down on conversions why
should we have conversions in India who
the hell are you to tell us we should
have this or that we you know the basic
principle that underpins the so-called
World rules based International order is
sovereignty and sovereignty means every
nation can decide what happens
internally without external interference
but the Americans are trying to
undermine the sovereignty of various
Nations including
India India is one of the only four
nations that is truly Sovereign but the
Americans are trying to undermine that
undermine India's sovereignty by
pressurizing India by putting out the
statements and then using the statements
to arm twist India diplomatically behind
closed doors and the Americans have the
ability to destroy entire economies and
they're also doing certain things in
India's Far East in Manipur and India is
not able to counter that right now so
India needs to work hard to become a
major economic power because with your
economic might comes your military
muscle so India is going to be at the
mercy of more powerful Nations until we
are a 1520 trillion economy which is at
least 20 years in the future so all of
you need to work hard all of us need to
work hard together and go in that
direction okay Malik Sayad says uh isn't
it that Indians are very much fair
skinned but but due to low living
standards most Indians have Sun damaged
skin look India is a gigantic Nation
gigantic region there are peoples of
people of every kind of skin color eye
color whatever in India you have people
in the northern regions who have much
fairer skin because of the lack of
sunlight compared to parts of Southern
India
Etc and there's so much genetic
diversity India is the highest genetic
diversity outside of Africa so that's
why India has such a diverse population
of such different skin colors
appearances uh body types height so much
more um of course people who are more
exposed to sunlight people who work
Outdoors regularly or whatever they will
have a greater sun exposure and
obviously their skin will be darker and
maybe some of them if they are naturally
predisposed to having lighter skin then
they may get sun damage like whatever
you know
sunburns and whatever else yeah so it's
because of various conditions I don't
think everybody in India is exposed to
Sun all the time there are lots of
people especially in metropolitan cities
who spent most of the time
indoors um so they won't face this
situation people who are farmers for
example who do daily farming out in the
fields they will obviously have darker
skin because of the constant sun
exposure some of them could have sun
damage and solve so it depends on your
occupation on your lifestyle on your
specific Indian genetics and so much
more hello I'm drunk drunk says do the
bishnu prya manipuri people share the
same history as the M people probably
not too
much okay okay there's a whole dispute
and controversy over there on who are
the true manipur's I'll tell you what
the true manipur's are the people of
Manipur the mes of Manipur bishnu prya
manipuri is probably not that
much
okay let's take a few more questions
then we will end at the 90minut
Mark we will not talk about Fusion
weapons tested on being tested on
populations of people okay we should
it's not appropriate to discuss that
okay so I will not take that question
imanu
says India World Cup yes India is going
to win we're GNA win World Cup final the
final match starts in about what 40
minutes India is going to win no offense
in South Africa anybody from South
Africa who may be watching no offense we
we are great friends of South Africa but
this World Cup final India is going to
win i w i i have watched a few World Cup
finals which was the last one I watched
I watched the 20111 World Cup final that
India won I watched the 2007 T20 final
that India won you know jendra shma if
anybody remembers him he took the World
Cup winning Wicket with his final ball
in international cricket when mbah hak
played that weird shot iconic moment so
I I believe India is going to have
another great moment
today ask history says uh could you give
some tips on how Indian Hindu citizens
can save Hinduism practice
Hinduism connect with other Hindus and
so on it is our ancient culture religion
everything the oldest religion in the
world obviously deserves to exist far
into the future and just saying that
doesn't mean that I have anything
against any other religion It's My
Religion it's the religion the
civilizational religion of the entire
subcontinent the world's oldest religion
it is a Global treasure it should thrive
so my point is reconnect with your
culture and Heritage what are your
sacred texts read them familiarize
yourself with them make sure that your
friends and relatives read that and and
spread it and if you have money build
temples or whatever right you know
that's how we do it through actions not
by talk by
Talking so yes what needs to happen
actually is that rich Hindu people
should invest actual money in
strengthening Hinduism in in society
maybe build more temples or
whatever Indian history says why doesn't
Modi replace Gandhi with nitaj and
revamp the education system I think Mr
Modi has to answer the question I cannot
answer on his behalf I I don't care
about the symbolism of having Gandhi on
this on the currency notes you know
there are civilized countries where the
great scientists like Oiler like
Einstein Etc are on the currency notes
that's what a civilized country does you
know having politicians
everywhere in India every every stadium
is named after some politician or the
other I'm not naming any specific
Stadium I'm saying generally if you look
at stadiums in India they are named
after various political
figures uh currency notes you only have
Mr
Gandhi listen I I I can't answer the
this question only Mr Modi can do it
revamping the education it's a very
tough job it'll take at least 20 years
maybe 50 years you got to started
somewhere you've been in power 10 years
you didn't do a thing about that your
new education policy is is a joke it
doesn't address any of the real issues
so I think only Mr Bodi can answer that
question I
can't
um sha says do you think India will be
given permanent member status at the UNC
UNC no nobody will give you anything
nobody gives you a thing in the world
please my dear children understand this
nothing is given for free you want
something you got to go and take it grab
it with your own two
hands you know you don't get something
for free why should anybody give you
something even if you deserve it if you
deserve something do you mean do you
think it means you'll get it
automatically you're going to fight for
everything even the things you deserve
so India will be given
nothing India will be given nothing
India will not be given permanent member
status of the UNC no it's not going to
happen so what's the solution you become
so powerful that the UN Security Council
becomes irrelevant comp in face of in in
in the presence of your power that's
what you have to do you have to make
these things irrelevant by becoming
powerful stop going and begging for this
oh please give me this little status
symbol give me that little status symbol
forget about all that you have to pursue
power real power and then everything
falls in place so India is going to get
nothing and we should stop asking for
it what
else uh hinga says how to work on my
speaking skills to speak like you did
you put some work on yours I put in work
every single live stream the more you
speak the better you get uh I've never
been much of a speaker in my life most
of the speaking I've done is on my live
streams and whatever public thing I do
somewhere or the other listen you want
to get you want to improve any skill
whether it is playing guitar whether it
is playing football whether it is
bowling whether it is mathematics
whether it is peing whether it is
whatever swimming any skill that you
want to improve you have to practice
practice practice
endlessly the the more you do it the
more natural it gets and then you will
reach your potential in that so how to
work on your speaking skills my dear
friend speak speak speak okay maybe you
don't have an audience today speak in
front of the mirror give a one hour
lecture in front of the mirror about
something and find a bunch of friends
and force them to listen to your
speeches and then as you get better you
can do it in front of bigger audiences
and know and so on so forth that's how
we do it the key to improving your
skills is to practice practice practice
endlessly the more the better that's how
you do it speaking of
whatever rakasi rajaj says why did
settler colonialism similar to what
happened in the US not take place in
India during British colonial rule
because of the Indian population density
and the Europeans could not tolerate the
Indian climate which was too harsh for
them and India had a significant
population density when it comes to
North America what's the number of North
Americans natives killed between 50 to
100 million but it's an entire continent
sized piece of land India is a
subcontinent sized piece of land India
was even then probably the highest it
had some of the highest population
densities in the world so what around
1800 or something what was India's
population unified India the whole
subcontinent including gandar including
Pakistan Bangladesh Etc the total
population of India would have been been
350 million today it is way more than
that and China would have a similar
population density in those days so
India was already highly populated it
had a climate that the British the
Europeans did not really like too much
it was too much it was way warmer for
them than they could tolerate and so
that's why they did not want to settle
down in India they wanted to Simply
extract India's
resources and that's what they did when
it comes to North America the climate
was more to their taste more to their
liking and maybe the people there were
less numerous the population density was
much lower in over time they just got
rid of the
people yeah so that's the reason why and
I'm sure there are more points you could
bring into
that
uh ask history asks a question Indian
history asks the same question
do you think Modi 3.0 will be as
effective as Modi 2.0 1.0 every Modi
term is different right Modi the first
term was about the Prime Minister and
and his government getting the hang of
how things are done in
Delhi um Modi 2.0 was about working on
building on top of what was achieved in
Modi 1.0 Modi 2. 3.0 is different it's
it's a coalition government Mr Modi for
the first time in his in his entire
career has not acquired a full majority
and now he has a coalition government it
doesn't mean is very very weak obviously
somewhat diminished one would say but
still a powerful government I'm sure and
whether he will be effective or not I
think it will determine the future of
India he better be effective because if
Modi Mr Modi and his government don't
bring in major changes and reforms in
India and bring India to a much higher
level in in the next two to five years
the BJP won't come to power again that
that is a
possibility so I think it is a matter of
rival for for Mr Modi and for his
political party BJP they better be
effective they better bring in more
results than they brought in in Modi
2.0 despite it being a college
government and there was talk about the
first 100 days of the government being
very effective and lots of changes
happening well we have not seen that
thus far but there's a long way to go
for the first 100
days so uh my my answer is it better be
much more effective than the 2.0
otherwise 2029 big question as to who
becomes the prime minister or which
party comes to
power and I'm optimistic like I've said
I'm an optimistic person I am optimistic
it'll be a great term okay let's take
one or two more questions and we
done
uh swk says my thoughts on ooso I think
fascinating guy fascinating man very
very sharp person maybe an IQ of one 70
I don't know and a guy who understood
India really really well and great
speaker Etc did he did he have any
spiritual mystical religious Etc Powers
I don't know about that but a very
interesting person and I I don't know
much about him I have not spent any time
reading his right reading his writings
or listening to his speeches but
whatever little I've seen I think he was
a brilliant person very interesting
person fascinating person uh yeah and of
course he was brought Low by people in
his Entourage which is a whole different
story okay something I have not answered
let's take one more question before we
end
this mcloven qu says your views on the
Delhi airport roof collapse extremely
unfortunate um needs to be investigated
and this is something that happens all
over
India and it should not be happening
it's because of low standards in India's
governance system system among India's
politicians and among India's
bureaucracy low
standards and I'll not elaborate further
but yes low standards and it should not
happen should I take one most one last
question sh says does India have a
chance of overtaking China in economy
and hard power yes in the next 20 years
we can do it next week won't happen next
two years won't happen it will need
multiple governments to continue along
the same politic same policies economic
policies then keep improving the
economic policies overall that needs to
happen and Military policies because we
need to invest in the military in the
Army Navy Air Force especially the Navy
we need to keep changing with the times
you do that over
multiple political terms fiveyear terms
then maybe in 20 years we will overtake
China historically we have always been
ahead of China the past 3 4,000 years
China has been around for 3,000 years
let's say three and a half thousand
years if you want to be charitable to
China as a civilization we have always
been the largest economy we India has
always been the world's largest economy
even the Americans and the British know
that look at Angus medicine the most
authoritative report historical report
on on the world's economy so it is our
natural position in the world to be the
largest
economy we don't think of it that way
because we are totally brainwashed we
have a tremendous inferiority complex we
Indians we think we don't deserve
anything good because we are not taught
what we were historically okay
so India should be the world's largest
economy obviously we have a chance it is
in our blood that we are the world's
largest economy so we have to just work
together and make it happen and we need
to re elect the right people and our
leaders need to do what we are voting
voting for them for so yeah that's what
okay Malik said says who are the true
people people of Maharashtra the two
people true people of mahra are the
maharan people what else I mean thec the
descendants of the maratas the
descendants of
the of
the what
okay uh which was the
dynasty the yadavas was it
look the the people of
Maharashtra are the descendant of the
maratas and whoever else lived in the
region at the time at the end of the day
we are all intermixed okay we have been
around in the same place for minimum
10,000 years if not 70,000 years so we
all have shared genetics we are all the
same people actually and the people who
today in today's world I would say the
people who speak marati as the mother
tongue are the true people of
Maharashtra that's all
all right
um okay I think I'm going to stop it
here I know there are so many more
questions but we have another live
stream stream tomorrow and we can take
more questions there so I in tomorrow's
live stream I will take maybe 15
questions or 20 questions from the
comments and the rest I will take live
so and tomorrow's live stream is is at
the regular time 9:00 p.m so I will see
you then maybe we'll take many more
questions at that time but for today I'm
going to end the live stream now because
we have a World Cup final coming up so I
hope we win that and I'm going to be
watching that at least some of it all
right so let's end this here thank you
so much for watching thank you for all
your questions and I will see you in the
next live stream and please keep raising
your standards don't be satisfied with
the status quo we can always do better
all right I'll see you tomorrow bye